







Jump to Section

Last Active: 12-Jun-20

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Last Modified: 21-Jan-20

## Summary

A CSPO/CBAP/CCBA certified, accomplished IT professional with in-depth experience of 9 years, presently performing in the capacity of Lead Business Analyst with Harman International Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore.

Comprehensive domain grasp across all the functional areas and expertise in Business Analysis, Requirements Analysis, and Elicitation, Business Analysis Planning, Requirements Management, Requirement Communication, Solution Assessment and Validation.

Have full knowledge and understanding of the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC).

Worked in both plan-driven (waterfall) and change driven environment (Agile development).

Preparation of SRS (System Requirements Specification Documentation), Business Plans, BRDs (Business

Requirement Documents), User Stories, User Manuals, Epics, Acceptance Test Criterion.

Have extensive work experience in business modeling, requirements modeling and data modeling.

Leading and liaison meeting between the client and the internal stakeholders.

## **Work Experience**

- Harman Connected Services as Product Owner Lead Business Analyst Dec 2014 to Till Date
  - Working in BDD and Agile(SCRUMS) frameworks.
  - Accountable for Product Roadmap, Backlog Management, Feature Prioritization.
  - Accountable for Release/Sprint Planning, Grooming, Daily Scrums, Retro and Reviews(Feature Demos).
- Accountable for Requirements Elicitation and Management.
- Accountable for writing the requirements in User Story, BDD and ACTDD formats.
- Accountable for UAT and post-production support.
- Responsible for GTM activities.
- Using various business analysis techniques like Brainstorming, Interviews and Requirement Workshops.
- Creating documents with help UML diagrams like Activity, State, and Sequence diagram.
- Experience in JIRA Confluence. Trello and AHA
- Experience in using tools like VISIO, Balsamiq and Draw.io.
- Medplus India Pvt. Ltd. as Business Analyst

Mar 2012 to Dec 2014

Key Projects Handled: MedPlus Mart, MedPlus Beauty, CRM, Rite Cure and Delivery Management Application

Technical Tools: Atlassian Jira and Atlassian Confluence Domain Knowledge: ERP, eCommerce Projects, Java Projects

Environment: Open Source ERP, Spring and Java

### Responsibilities:

Conducted stakeholder analysis.

Gathered requirements from the stakeholders using a variety of effective techniques like interviews, JAD, requirement

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. שטווסווטעס.

Responsible for defining as-is and to-be process flows and performing gap analysis.

Involved in facilitating the requirement workshops and Joint Application Developments with COO, CTO, development team, testing team and UI Designers.

Elicited requirements using various requirements documents like Business Requirement Document, Functional Requirement Specification, Meeting Minutes and SRS.

Documented the functional and business requirements using UML diagrams like DFD, Activity Diagram, Sequence Diagram and State Diagram.

Involved in prototyping the user interfaces for the Operations area of the company.

Communicated the requirements to all the stakeholders through the requirements package and involved in seeking approval on them.

Accountable for work distribution among the team members & handled the project related activities and production issues.

Worked with the testing team to demonstrate the requirements and reviewed the test cases.

Accountable for UAT and post implementation support to the client.

Worked on post implementation issues using root cause analysis and managed them using problem tracking.

Demonstrated all newly implemented processes to the client and the operational team and prepared user manuals to help them understand the processes.

Working on projects executed using waterfall methodologies.

Deftly managed multiple projects, ensured successful completion of the projects within the approved timelines and smooth execution and implementation of the Project.

Involved in managing the business analysis and project scope.

Worked in all the phases of SDLC and has the ability to adhere to project methodologies, testing and documentation.

Collaborated with the team members and senior management to maintain a continuous stream of information

regarding the project status and progress & identified appropriate solutions for problems if any

Responsible for handling various project management activities like maintaining project checklists, project charter and managing change requests.

Worked on the various aspects of ERP like Order Management, Inventory Management, Catalog Management, Order Returns, Promotion Engine and Payments Integration across all verticals.

Have sound knowledge about all the eCommerce functionalities like Checkout, Customer Account Management, Single Sign On and Cataloging.

Used various business analysis techniques root cause analysis, benchmarking, problem tracking, interviews, brainstorming, estimation, interface analysis, document analysis, traceability matrix, checklists, functional decomposition, process modeling, requirement workshops.

## Hotwax Media Pvt. Ltd as Business Analyst

Sep 2008 to Aug 2011

Key Projects Handled: ALX Global, Scarpa Pro America, Product Bahn, Moxii, Buynow

Technical Tools: Atlassian Jira and Atlassian Confluence Domain Knowledge: ERP, eCommerce Projects

Environment: Open Source ERP (Ofbiz)

#### Responsibilities:

Responsible for gathering requirements from the Client through brainstorming, emails, conference calls and interviews

Ensured high productivity by understanding client's business requirements and ensured better service level to enhance satisfaction and selling business.

Responsible for technical and functional gap analysis.

Elicited business, stakeholder, functional, non functional and transition requirements (for legacy data transitions) using BRDs, Epics, User Stories, Acceptance Tests, MoMs and SRS.

Communicated the requirements to all the stakeholders for review and seek formal sign off from them.

Accountable for providing the business analysis estimates using Function Point estimation technique and defining scope of business analysis work.

Worked on projects executed using agile methodology.

Worked in coordination with the Project Manager to prepare product backlog (using Rolling Wave Planning) and assigning resources to projects.

Worked in synch with the development team and testing team to help them understand the requirements and to provide functional support.

Accountable for UAT, test cases review and post implementation support.

Demonstrated newly implemented functionalities to the Client and developed user manuals to help them run the processes.

Managed all the post implementation issues using Jira and problem management technique.

Assessed the solution (post implementation) to provide suggestion for improvements.

Successfully completed the assignments within the defined time frame and garnered sound experience in managing techno-commercial aspects.

Mentored junior business analyst and reviewed requirements specifications prepared by them.

Used various business analysis techniques root cause analysis, benchmarking, problem tracking, data glossary, interviews, brainstorming, estimation, interface analysis, document analysis, user stories and acceptance and evaluation criterion.

^ Back to Top

## **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Devi Ahilya Vishwa Vidhyalaya (DAVV), Indore in 2005

PG: MBA/PGDM (Computer Management) from Devi Ahilya Vishwa Vidhyalaya (DAVV), Indore in 2007

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

CCBA certified

CSPO

CBAP

^ Back to Top

## IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience
ATI ASSIAN JIRA 0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

/ (I D DON 11 0 II V )		0 1001(0) 0 1101101(0)
CONFLUENCE		0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SCRUM		0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
PRODUCT MANAGEMENT		0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
BUSINESS ANALYSIS		
Requirement GATHERING		
Requirement elicitation		
User Acceptance Testing		
BDD		0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Agile Methodology	0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			

^ Back to Top

## **Affirmative Action**

## **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No

 $\ensuremath{\mathsf{US}}$  Work Status: Authorized to Work in the  $\ensuremath{\mathsf{US}}$ 

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.